Colt McManis

Graphic Designer

A senior sports graphic designer at Ohio University with a minor in marketing. Demonstrates expertise as a graphic designer at Ohio University Football and through an internship with the St. Louis Surge. Brings a distinct blend of creativity, adaptability, and precision. Focused on passionately crafting visually compelling designs through capturing the essence of sports. Wants to work professionally for an organization that shares this passion.

Work Experience

St. Louis Surge GWBA Basketball (May 2023–August 2023)

- Graphic Design Intern

Lead the design of all graphics for social media and print, ensuring a cohesive visual representation of the team throughout the season. Executed designs within the framework of a team's brand identity. Acquired valuable experience in an office setting, actively collaborating with cross-functional teams.

Ohio University Football (February 2023–Present)

- Graphic Designer

Contributes to the creation of social graphics for a Division 1 FBS program, always consistently upholds the team's visual identity across various platforms.

Demonstrates proficiency in working within prescribed style structures and incorporates feedback into design iterations.

1716 Digital (October 2021-February 2022)

- Graphic Designer

Led the design of promotional graphics for an Indiegogo page, enhancing the visual appeal and effectiveness of the campaign. Developed on-screen graphics, showcasing adaptability in various design applications.

Demonstrated an ability to receive constructive feedback and iteratively enhance designs.

Sherwin Williams (April 2021–Present)

- Retail Color Consultant

Provides color consultations to customers, utilizes a deep understanding of color theory.

Demonstrates excellent customer service qualities by actively listening to customer needs.

Exemplifies problem-solving skills by addressing customer concerns in an efficient manner.

Contact

10 Milliron St. Apt A5 Athens, OH 45701 740-577-4104 coltmcmedia@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/coltmcmanis

Education

BFA in Graphic Design Ohio University Athens, Ohio

Minor in Marketing Ohio University Athens, Ohio

Skills

Adobe InDesign
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe After Effects
Adobe Bridge
Adobe Camera Raw
Visual Studio Code (html,
css, and js)
Photography

Languages

English – Native Spanish – Learning



Exhibitions

Who Gets to Decide? 2023

London Ramparts

Mixed Media

39th annual Foothills Art Festival 2021

Untitled I, Untitled II

Digital Photograph(s)

Awards & Scholarships

39th annual Foothills Art Festival 2021
3rd Place Amateur 2D (Untitled I)

Ohio University Dean's List

Fall 2020, Spring/Fall 2021, Spring/Fall 2022, Spring/Fall 2023

Ohio Promise Award Scholarship

2020-2021, 2021-2022, 2022-2023, 2023-2024

Ohio Distinction Scholarship

2020-2021, 2021-2022, 2022-2023, 2023-2024

Ohio Success Scholarship

2020-2021, 2021-2022, 2022-2023, 2023-2024

Ohio Together Scholarship

2020-2021, 2021-2022, 2022-2023, 2023-2024

Scottish Rite Scholarship

2021, 2022, 2023

Professional Memberships

Member

AIGA (American Institute of Graphic Arts)

Member

APA (American Planning Association)

References

Kyle Pollock

Director of Recruiting

Ohio University Football

Current Supervisor

Athens, Ohio

pollockk@ohio.edu

908-472-1580

Nina Rodriguez

Director of Operations

St. Louis Surge

Former Supervisor

St. Louis, Missouri

operations@stlsurgebasketball.com

618-698-8750

Mark Franz

Professor of Graphic Design

Ohio University College of Fine Arts

Former Professor

Athens, Ohio

franzm@ohio.edu

317-363-5008

JP Rhea

Professor of Graphic Design

Ohio University College of Fine Arts

Current Professor

Athens, Ohio

jprhea@ohio.edu

770-355-3432

Chris Davis

Store Manager

Sherwin Williams Paint Store

Current Supervisor

Athens, Ohio

sw701953@sherwin.com

740-336-5142

